Steve McNatt

Data Scientist

Madison, WI

608-772-7651 | ssmcnatt@gmail.com LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

SUMMARY

I enjoy gathering, cleaning, and organizing data in a corporate environment and analyze it to answer important stakeholder questions and improve processes and profitability. My goal is to start a career as a Data Scientist/Data Analyst and work at the same company for many years.

I am an expert in software development processes and methodologies including analysis, design, development, testing, debugging, installation, maintenance, and support on multiple IT systems and programming languages. I have excellent interpersonal, verbal and written communication skills.

SKILLS

Data Science: Python, SQL, Jupyter, Pandas, Seaborn, NumPy, Matplotlib, Data Analytics, Machine Learning, Regression (Linear, Logistic, Analysis), Linear Models, A/B Testing, Supervised and Unsupervised Learning

Web Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Software Development: Java, Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), Troubleshooting, SAP ERP, ABAP

Tools: Git/GitHub, VS Code, Microsoft Office, Microsoft Excel

PROJECTS

Experimental Design project for Thinkful Data Science course | The PMRC Effects on Music Popularity

https://github.com/ssmcnatt/experimental-design-cap01

Supervised Learning project for Thinkful Data Science course | Predicting NFL Game Outcomes

https://github.com/ssmcnatt/nfl-supervised-learning-cap02

EXPERIENCE

Best Buy | Madison, WI

Geek Squad Agent

2012

 Provided Windows and iOS/Mac software installation and troubleshooting, wireless assistance, anti-virus assistance, PC hardware repair and builds

TDS Corporate | Middleton, WI

Senior Systems Analyst / Programmer

1999 - 2009

- Developed and maintained SAP software, plug-ins, and extensions using my SDLC skills of analysis, design, development, testing, implementation and support for multiple SAP modules including: Materials Management (MM), Financial Accounting (FI), Supply Chain Management (SCM, Retail), Production Planning (PP), Sales and Distribution (SD), Treasury (TR), and Human Resources (HR)
- Directed and advised software developers as the Programming Team Lead in the SAP upgrade from 4.5B to 4.6C, reduced the software support work by 20% by eliminating obsolete and unused programs
- Created and implemented the Secure Report Distribution System, a web-based front-end application for end-users to view reports directly and securely
- Drove training for new software developers and consultants
- Developed multiple inbound and outbound interfaces for an outsourced benefits management company
- Led the move from SAP to Tidal job scheduling including over 200 batch jobs

Comprehensive Computer Consulting | Sun Prairie, WI

Programmer Analyst Consultant

1995 - 1999

- **Georgia Pacific, Wisconsin Rapids, 1995-1997:** Analyzed, designed, developed, tested, implemented, and supported the scheduling and manufacturing systems
- TDS Corporate, Middleton, WI, 1997-1999: Designed, developed and supported SAP software in all of the following SAP modules: Materials Management (MM), Financial Accounting (FI - General Ledger, Accounts Payable, Accounts Receivable), and Treasury (TR)

Eaton Corporation | Milwaukee, WI

Programmer Analyst

1990 - 1994

- Collaborated directly with users to design, develop, implement, troubleshoot, and support manufacturing systems
 to create systems that met the needs of the warehouse staff
- Provided training to users

EDUCATION

Thinkful

Data Science Immersion

December, 2020

- Full time online course in Data Science
- Python and SQL using Jupyter Notebook, PostgreSQL, pgAdmin, Git, GitHub
- Experimental design, data cleaning, data exploration, machine learning

freeCodeCamp

January, 2020 - May, 2020

Python, JavaScript, data visualization, front end libraries, APIs

YWeb Career Academy, Madison, WI

June, 2019 - December, 2019

- Full time bootcamp in Web Design and Development
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React using Visual Studio Code and Node .JS
- Certificate of Completion received December, 2019

Madison College (MATC), Madison, WI

- Java Programming
- Advanced Java Programming

University of Wisconsin, Madison, WI

• Bachelor of Science (BS), Computer Science